So hello friends how are you all so today
we are in interview with Rishabh bhai so brother brother he is
working in II Bank and
we have specially taken time from him so that today we can tell you all
how we can apply in II Bank even if
you are a fresher candidate
ok Rishabh bhai first tell me
how are you I am very well how are
you Kavil bhai hello everyone yes sir
I am also fine and first of all
thank you for
coming here to our channel to help all our candidates so let us
start now first of all we
want to know something about you that means
when did you join II Bank I joined ICICI
Bank in 2020 it is about to be approximately four years for me
in ICICI Bank and
my first posting was at Jalandhar location
so I joined there as an infrastructure
and facility manager because
I did my graduation in civil
engineering so there I was 45  I was
handling the branches. I was looking after the
lease signing and the infrastructure and
project of that branch. And I mean, like you,
you joined as a fresher candidate
here. Yes, I
joined the bank as a fresher. Okay, so when
you joined, did you take anyone's
reference or how did you join? Actually,
my joining was
through a reference.
I have a friend who referred my CV. After that, I got
a call from HR. My interview took place. I was
called for GD. After that,
I was finally shortlisted.
My background was from civil engineering,
that's why I was selected for the project. So,
now when candidates are
listening to all this, I get a lot of questions like,
Sir, you tell me about the job but it is
not possible to get it without a reference. So, first of all, I
want to address this query. Now,
as you told me that you went
through a reference.  Candidates
want to know, "Sir, if we do
n't have any references, right?" So, if we have to
go and apply, can we also
apply to ICICI Bank and get a job like this?
What's the best part of the bank?
You get two options here,
apart from references. I'm not talking about that. The
first option is to go to the IC Bank Limited
career site. If
you're a fresher or have experience, the
bank also works for freshers and provides
them opportunities. You can go there and
upload your CV.
When HR thoroughly recruits your CV,
you'll get a call based on your profile.
Secondly, we
also have a provisional officer program in the bank,
which you join. It's a one-year
program. This is your Bangalore
location, in which you're
cleared for banking terms. You become
sound with banking terms,
which leads to the bank hiring you directly for the position of deputy manager.
And secondly, if you
want to move to a lower position, for example,
if you  If you don't want to pursue a
one-year course, there's also a 45-day
course of approximately this duration,
through which you can
join a bank as a sales officer or senior officer.
I
made a video earlier using both of these programs.
Now, many candidates ask, "
Sir, what are the difficulties in this? We
get a job." If you're
working internally, these programs really
work. I mean, this program is very good for candidates.
I honestly want to tell
my friends that this program is the best.
Especially after 12th, you can do a B.Sc. or B.Com.
After graduation, their
criteria is a minimum of 55 percent. They have
n't made the criteria very wide, at 55 percent. If
you have a minimum of 55 percent, then you can go for this program.
Your steps are simple. First, you have a written
exam, which checks your basic aptitude, reasoning,
and basic
computer knowledge.
After that, if you will get clear the exam, they will
call you for the group discussion and
interview and the best part is that I felt that actually what I felt during
my
interview is that they do not check your knowledge
in the interview, your knowledge is
checked in the exam part, so the
best part is that in the interview they
check your confidence, so I
think cracking the interview is
not a big task, if your basic
aptitude is clear then you can easily join
IIC Bank as a Deputy
Manager, now we have talked
about the programs, see, it is
clear till here that if the candidate
goes through the program then it will be good for him,
now suppose what a person did,
he applied through career, okay,
as I keep telling in the videos,
apply through career, then
after that he will have an interview, so we
want to know a little bit that
what are the rounds in the interview, what kind of
questions are there, if you tell me this, it
depends on whether you are being
interviewed as a fresher or  The
second thing is the
profile they are interviewing you for.
If they are interviewing you at the SO level, then maybe
there will be
a single round. Your interviewer may be
your reporting partner,
or the
zonal head of that department may be interviewing you. So, you will have a
single interview for that post. But if you are
going for a bigger post, like at the
zonal level or AGM level, then maybe there can be
two or three
rounds. And this also happens, like
now most of the candidates prefer
in the beginning that sir, we want to go
into branch banking, like a cashier's job
or a relationship manager's job, so if
you tell me something for this job, then
I can only say that you can give
your point, you
can give your preference as to where you want to go, which
department or which profile,
but it totally depends on the HR,
your interview, your background. For example,
my background was from engineering,
so they hired me for the project manager role.  If
I had gone as a cashier, ideally
I don't think I would have been able to fit in logically. So,
on the basis of your background and your interview, the HR will advise you on the best role and
you can join it. For example, if you are a
CA applicant or a CA candidate, then
credit is the best option for him. Now if
you give the cost of cashier to a CA, then I do
n't think that will be okay for that
candidate. So, it is not our point to think about
which one we have to go into. The
HR will allocate us the best profile for us.
Meaning, now the thing to understand is that what
I wanted to explain to the candidates here through
this question is what to do here.
If someone is going to a bank and
applying on a career basis, then he should give an
interview. After giving the interview, the
HR will decide
which post is suitable for him according to his qualification.
Meaning, right,
for a candidate, it will be rather that
he says from the beginning, no ma'am, I
want this post only. Sir, I want this very post.  I want this post
at least, so this is fine, this is your
recommendation, yes, I found it good and
if we talk about qualifications, minimum graduation is
required, right? Yes, minimum
graduation is required and as per your
graduation, the banks
recruit you, so basic
graduation is required and if you have post
graduation then that is a plus point for you only
and if there is anything for a 12th pass out candidate, there is no
such chance, there is no such thing for 12th pass out candidate,
in the banking sector
you deal with all types of customers,
they can be from a good business background or
from a service background,
so the bank's thought is that a graduate
candidate can easily handle all types of
customers, the bank has only one
objective and that is customer
satisfaction. I
would like to say that target and pressure are there
in every organization and I do
n't think there will be any organization in
which there is no talk of target and we
know the problem  It is not the companies' problem, I will
say frankly the problem is within us
that we see a target in this way as a
challenge but the target itself is such a
plus point which pushes us forward
for an achievement because
if we have to set a benchmark in our career then it can only be
through a target. For
example, if my senior has given me a target, for example, my
target here is 95 but I have to resolve queries,
if I am able to achieve even 94 then it becomes
my benchmark that my achievement at 94
is my own which satisfies me
and pushes me to do my best in future.
If there is no benchmark then
I know that we are the
best lawyers for ourselves, you must also agree with this, so
if there is no benchmark then we will
always justify our performance as the best, even
if we are not good, so I
feel that the target is a plus point
and we have to take it in a positive way
and for that I would like to say one point
along with it that it depends a little bit on
us.  It is about the leader,
okay, the touchwood who has been my leader,
he always gave me a positive
environment due to which
my target never seemed like a target to me, it seemed like
an achievement to me,
he always guided me and gave
me the right direction due to which I was able to
crack it easily with their support, so it depends on us in
which way we are looking at that thing,
basically the thing is that the
candidates who ask questions like this from the beginning, that is, a
person who is
working in a bank,
tells the other, that is, the new person who comes, that
friend, don't come here, the target has been made
in our life since childhood, like when we
qualify 10th, then we have a
target there, we have to clear it with first division, we have our
own target,
we have to clear 12th with first division, we have to
graduate, we have our own vision
that we want to become a banker, we want to
become a CA, for that also we
create our own benchmark, so this is a
plus point, so I  I would
like to tell my friend that you should take this in a positive way
and you should
grow yourself in your career on the basis of that target. Now let
us talk about the target clearly, it means whoever
comes knows that I have to work,
I have to achieve further, then I will be able to do
things further. So, the government is
giving targets right now, I mean all the government sectors are also
working well, I mean they are also
giving target based competition, yes yes,
no, okay and this is the thing, now
see, if targets are coming, everything is
coming, then along with this, we want to know
how much the candidates will be able to earn,
if a fresher candidate comes, then how much
starting salary can he take,
see that, if we talk about salary, then
it depends totally on your
knowledge, your skills and your
experience.
Well, if
I talk about salary, then there is a capping, from
this grade to this grade, you have this much
capping, but it totally depends on
your own.  On the knowledge front, if I have sound
knowledge and I can
prove myself to be a perfect fit for this profile, then
definitely the company will offer me a good package.
If I am not a perfect fit for it,
then there may be a little bit less
in comparison to others. So talking about salary,
banking sector gives a good salary and a
good package and it totally depends on
your own knowledge. If
you have sound knowledge, then you can easily get a good package. I
mean, as I have seen my
friends who used to work, that is, they are working in banks.
Now, I have also
given interviews etc. So, I think what I
wanted to say is that a fresher candidate's
starting salary will be minimum 14 to 15000, even
if he gets a normal post. I would
like to tell you that 141, as you
pointed out here, I think they can
get even better than this because there are some people in my team who have joined as a fresher.
I will not disclose their salary,
but yes, their average salary is  It is approximately Rs. 25 per month,
okay, because it
depends on your knowledge and for
which profile you are, are you coming to the bank as an
off-roll or on-roll, there are
many roles here and
how much the bank is offering you for which role will
depend on your knowledge and
Rishabh Bhai, I think one plus point in a bank is
that the incentive here becomes quite good
if a person does good work,
if I am talking about ICICI Bank, then the
plus point of ICICI Bank, I think is that
in the eyes of the bank, they consider all the employees
equal, so here there is
no incentive part for the employees, I am talking about the on-roll
staff because
they believe that all our staff is working
equally, so the bank has given an annual bonus to the employee, it
comes in your salary from the bank's side, so it is
equal for every employee, it is not like that,
even the bank does not do this, you will target
you so much  Incentive will be given because the bank
's thought is that each of our employees is
doing good work positively, which means
that yes, we have seen
what happens in other banks and other companies, that the
manager gets more incentive and the junior
level gets less, so I mean, IIC Bank has done it in
this way, that I found it to be a plus
point of the bank because the bank looks equal to everyone from senior level to
lower level, that
every employee is equal and is
contributing equally to the profit of the bank,
so you get an annual bonus from the bank's
side, so now see, we have discussed everything,
now we are moving towards the end, which means
basically, if we talk about what you have talked about, then it may be a
little difficult for a fresher candidate to
understand, that we have talked about the
target and all the conclusion, we do this that
if a fresher is coming to apply,
he can apply through Career Pay, that is one way,
secondly, you told us that what we  There are
programs like your PO program and
a 45 day program that can come through that
and thirdly, he
can also approach for reference if he
goes to a bank or talks to someone for
reference, you can do this,
like direct hiring also happens,
like in branch banking, if you are getting
hired directly, sometimes you
visit the branch for services, then
your manager there, the officer with whom
you are talking, you can talk to them once,
whether there is anyone hiring there, then on that
basis also they can refer you,
tell me one thing in HR, like in
my videos, I
tell most of the candidates that you
trust online, but I prefer them more
that you
go directly, if there are five to ten branches near you, there are
different ones too, if you want to
work in a bank in the banking sector, then
you should go directly, take your resume and
talk to them, if I have a job
requirement, then this has some plus points, that is,
they will get the person quickly  If we are
not able to get a job, what happens in that, like our staff,
for example, if someone comes to me, then
I can refer the HR directly there, so
when I refer, if I
refer someone personally, then
obviously the recruiter first looks at that thing,
once he overviews it, then
definitely the call also comes quickly
for that and I would like to say that the staff
is very supportive, if you visit
ICICI Bank for any support, then the
staff will definitely support you, if there are multiple
qualities then the HR will overview you
and now the last question is that
which quality, like a candidate has a question
that sir, I have done BA or
B.Com, now many say that I am a science
student or something like that, then
for whom is it preferred to go into the banking sector
and who should stay in his field,
banking sector, we can say that
like there is an all-rounder in a cricketer,
similarly the banking sector is the best fit for everyone
because there are multiple departments here,
okay, so you can do that somewhere  You will
definitely fit somewhere, but maybe
you are suitable for branch banking. If you are
from the sales department and have done your MBA in
sales or finance, then you
can fit in branch banking. Or you
can also go to the risk analyst department. So you can fit in every department. There are
multiple departments, which is
fine for you. That means the bank will accommodate everyone. Go and give an
interview, and you will be done. Yes, yes,
this is our proper
point from today. If you
want to say more to some candidates, you
can say something. Now, in the end, I would
just like to say this to my friends that
when you are doing your graduation,
if you are preparing for something, then
just keep your foundation a little sound, your
basic knowledge because
I would like to give only one tip that
your knowledge is not seen in the interview.
Any company X, Y, etc. I will
not highlight any one company here.
Any company for which you are going for the
interview can work on your knowledge.
Okay, you  He is a fresher,
definitely see I was also a fresher once,
like you are a fresher now, every company
works on freshers, but you should have
confidence, there should be an eagerness to understand that thing, that
I have to do this,
I have to achieve this, I have to understand,
your communication should be good, the
interviewer only sees your communication, your
confidence, your eye contact, the
rest of the knowledge does not matter,
every company will work on you for knowledge, will make you sound, will
mold you, that is the
role of the manager to
mold his report as per the
requirement of the organization, so you should
never feel down about your knowledge,
go with your confidence and
fight the interview and if it is yours then
you will perform the best, so it means
that to go to the interview, the result should be good, one should have
good communication skills,
confidence should be within us,
confidence will make the eye contact, so
basically this is what it means and there are some such things also
like from my side  I want to say that it is
very important to have knowledge of your surroundings
because in most of the interviews I have given, the question
asked is that
which famous place is near you,
tell me, there is a reason for that, which
I understand that the person is looking at how much
awareness does the
candidate have, how aware is he about his surroundings, if for
example, I am not aware of my surroundings, then
I will not know what is happening with me in the organization, then that
too can be a weak point somewhere,
for me it is normal that we should be
aware of our surroundings,
I mean what the candidates do today is that
most of the
students, I mean, focus only on studies,
they read books, all the knowledge, not that the
company does not need much knowledge, so you do
not have to go into books,
you have acquired deep knowledge from books, but you are
not able to speak to the customer, as an
example, if you are in the banking sector, you
come to branch banking, you have
complete knowledge  You have proper knowledge but if you are
not able to communicate, are
not able to understand the customer's query, are
not able to resolve the query, then you are not fit
for that
role,
we are fine, so thank you so much Rishabh Bhai, you have taken out
your time for our candidates,
uh thank you, I should say that
you gave me the opportunity to
discuss some points with my friend today, my
thoughts, thank you Kapil
Bhai ji, and everyone else will learn things from you
and I believe that if
any candidate gets selected from this interview of ours
or
achieves something in life, then it will be a very big achievement,
absolutely, so you must tell in the comment section how
you liked it, which part of it has been
very useful to you
and if there is any such question which you
want us to answer, then you can
comment in the comment section, both of us, that is,
I will discuss it with Bhai,
if there is any such question, then reply to it.  I will
definitely give it to you too, so this was the complete
video of the interview, in the end let me tell you again that
Bhai has almost four years of
experience in IIC Bank, so the
things that he has
shared with you from his experience are absolutely real,
okay, because it is not something heard, the
reality has been told to you, so you just have to follow it
and move ahead in your career, so
thank you so much for watching this video, so let's meet
in the next video, till then
ok bye to all of you
[Music]